Hi, this is John Stewart, and this is how to tell people where you're going, and when you're going to be there.
When you go camping, you need to let other people know where you're going to be, how long you're going to be there, and when you're coming back.
These things are very important.
Once you decide that you want to go out camping, you need to tell people.
"Hey, I'm going to be on the Bushwhacker Trail, in the Morel Mountain State Park, in Kentucky."
Tell them very specific stuff.
If you're hiking a certain section of a trail, tell them what section you're going to be in.
Try and be real, real precise, so they know exactly where you are.
Tell them when you're leaving.
Let them know that you've left.
Tell them when you're supposed to be back.
If you're driving there, flying there, something like that.
This is key also, signing in at a ranger's office.
They're going to ask you to sign in, sign out, so that they know you're there, for that certain amount of time.
Also, don't just tell one person.
Don’t tell your wife.
Maybe tell your mom.
Tell your dad.
Tell your best friend.
Tell more than one person, so that in case someone forgets, someone else remembers that you're supposed to be back, and if you're not, they can send somebody out to look for you, so this is how to tell others about going camping.